Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA) Archived Website, Apr 28, 2009 - ongoing; American Guild of Musical Artists
  The American Guild of Musical Artists, AFL-CIO (AGMA), founded in 1936, is an American labor union that represents 8,000 current and retired opera singers, ballet and other dancers, opera directors, backstage production personnel at opera and dance companies, and figure skaters. AGMA is a branch of Associated Actors and Artistes of America. The website contains auditions listings, agreements and contracts, news and event listings, and information on meetings and board members.
  Performing artists |x labor unions |z United States.
- American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) Archived Website, Apr 23, 2012 - ongoing; American Guild of Variety Artists
  The American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) is an AFL-CIO-affiliated labor union founded in 1939 to represent performing artists and stage managers for live performances in the variety field. The variety area of performance includes singers and dancers in touring shows and in theatrical revues, theme park performers, skaters, circus performers, comedians & stand-up comics, cabaret & club artists, lecturers, poets, monologists, spokespersons, and variety performers working at private parties special events. AGVA is a branch of The Associated Actors and Artistes of America. AGVA negotiates contracts and provides relief for members. The website contains information on their relief funds, auditions, news, and other information.
  Entertainment industry.
- American Postal Workers Union (APWU) Archived Website, Dec 5, 2009 - ongoing; American Postal Workers Union
  The American Postal Workers Union (APWU), formed in 1971, represents more than 220,000 United States Postal Service employees and retirees, and nearly 2,000 private-sector mail workers. It represents employees of the United States Postal Service who are clerks, maintenance employees, and motor vehicle service workers. APWU works for decent pay, benefits, and safe working conditions for workers they represent. The APWU is a Union Network International and AFL-CIO affiliate.
  Postal service |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Archived Website, Mar 28, 2014-ongoing; Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance
  Founded in 1992, the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) was created to address the continued under-representation of Asian Pacific American (APA) workers in the labor movement and the specific challenges APA workers face. APALA works on projects related to voter registration, the DREAM Act, and workplace organizing. The website contains information on their executive board, youth leadership and organizing committees, press releases, news listings, convention information, and a blog.
  Asian Americans -- Economic conditions.; Asian Americans -- Employment.; Asian Americans -- Civil rights.; Asian American labor union members.; Asian Americans -- Politics and government.; Asian Americans -- Social conditions.
- Association of Flight Attendants (AFA-CWA) Archived Website, Dec 5, 2009 - ongoing; Association of Flight Attendants (U.S.)
  The Association of Flight Attendants-CWA (AFA-CWA), founded in 1945, is a union representing flight attendants in the United States. In 2011, AFA represents nearly 60,000 Flight Attendants at 23 airlines, making it the world's largest Flight Attendant union. The goal of flight attendants who become part of AFA-CWA is to negotiate better pay, benefits, working conditions, work rules at their airline, and to improve their safety on the job. The AFA is part of the Communication Workers of America (CWA), an affiliate with the AFL-CIO, and an affiliate of the 5 million member International Transport Workers' Federation.
  Flight attendants |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union (BCTGM) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union
  The Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers' International Union (BCTGM) is a labor union in the United States and Canada with a membership of 100,000. The union includes workers in bakeries, candy, cereal, sugar, grain mills, tobacco plants, food processing and manufacturing facilities and other related occupations related to these industries. The union traces its history to the founding of the Journeymen Bakers Union in 1886. The contemporary BCTGM was formed in January, 1999 from the merger of the Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers' International Union and the American Federation of Grain Millers. The BCTGM is affiliated with the AFL-CIO, the Canadian Labour Congress and the International Union of Food Workers (IUF).
  Tobacco workers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Bakery employees |x Labor unions.
- Black Workers for Justice Archived Website, May 8, 2011 - ongoing; Black Workers for Justice
  The Black Workers for Justice (BWFJ) is a mass activist workers organization. It includes socialists, radical working class and general members, who link the immediate struggles in the workplaces and communities to a long term transitional radical program for Black empowerment/self-determination, social justice and social transformation. BWFJ was founded in 1981. Its labor and political perspectives grow out of an analysis of the development of the U.S. national and global economy, the U.S. imperialist state, and the ongoing role of the U.S. South as a fundamental pillar of U.S imperialism.
  Black nationalism.; Community organization.; African American labor union members.
- Bread and Roses Cultural Project Archived Website, Aug 9, 2009; 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East
  Bread and Roses, part of the 1199SEIU, was founded in 1979, as a cultural resource for union members and students in New York City who would otherwise have little access to the arts. Bread and Roses established the only permanent union exhibition space in the nation, Gallery 1199, at the union's New York City headquarters. Bread and Roses appears to be defunct as of 2009.
  Hispanic American labor union members.; African American labor union members.; Labor in art.
- Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers Local 1 Archived Website, Dec 5, 2012 - ongoing; Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers, Local 1
  The International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 1 was granted a charter by the National Union of Bricklayers of the U.S.A. on October 17, 1868 in Brooklyn, New York and is one of the oldest continuously-existing locals in New York City. The union represents bricklayers, plasterers, stonesetters, and pointers, cleaners and caulkers. The website contains their newsletter, events, and news listings.
  Bricklayers -- Labor unions
- Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen (BRS) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen
  The Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen, founded in 1901, represents nearly 9,500 signal employees on both the freight railroads and the passenger and commuter railroads across the United States and into Canada. The Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen is affiliated with the AFL-CIO and the Transportation Trades Department.
  Railroads |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, (BCTD) Archived Website, Oct 25, 2012 - ongoing; AFL-CIO. Building and Construction Trades Department
  The Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, (BCTD) is the coordinating body of construction unions in the AFL-CIO. The department provides training and support to construction workers. It is made up of seven committees: Apprenticeship and Training; the Canadian Executive Board; General Presidents' Committee on Contract Maintenance; Labor-Management Committee; Legislative Task Force Committee; National Organizing Committee; and the Women in the Trades Committee. The website contains news, directories, legislative issues, and field services.
  Construction industry -- Labor unions -- United States.
- Building Trades Employers' Association of the City of New York. Archived Website, Feb 1, 2009 - ongoing; Building Trades Employers' Association
  Building Trades Employers Association (BTEA) is affiliated with 28 trade union contractor associations, representing the 1,700 construction managers, general contractors and specialty subcontractor firms in New York City, who employ 125,000 people. Members range in size from multi-billion dollar internationally recognized firms to small and mid-sized specialty trade contracting firms. The BTEA promotes safety, skill training, professional standards, and works to strengthen the economic vitality and social fabric of New York City.
  Building trades -- New York (State) -- New York; Employers' associations |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Caucus of Rank-and-File Educators Archived Website, Sep 12, 2012 - ongoing; Caucus of Rank-and-File Educators
  The Caucus of Rank and File Educators (CORE) is a coalition within the Chicago Teacher's Union that took power in the union in 2010. They are against school privatization and led the 2012 Chicago teacher's strike. The website contains news updates and a newsletter.
- Civil Service Merit Council Archived Website, Feb 6, 2009 - Mar 6, 2009; Civil Service Merit Council
  The Civil Service Merit Council, founded in 1971, is a non-partisan coalition of individuals and organizations whose primary purpose was to increase the level of efficiency and integrity of government. The Merit Councils primary objective is to ensure that all appointments to the New York civil service shall be made through competitive examinations to properly classified positions from among persons duly qualified without regard to race, religion, age, sex, or political opinion or affiliation. The Council is dedicated to preserving and advancing the rights and tenure of all persons in the Merit System.
  Civil service -- New York (State) -- New York.; Municipal officials and employees |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Civil Service Technical Guild, Local 375, DC 37, AFSCME - AFL-CIO Archived Website, Mar 5, 2009 - ongoing; Civil Service Technical Guild
  The Civil Service Technical Guild (Local 375, DC 37), founded in 1929, represents 7,000 engineers, architects, scientists, chemists, planners, and other technical inspectors working for the City of New York. The guild's goals include the prevention of the outsourcing city contracts, fighting for the adherence to civil service laws, enforcing contracts, and fighting privatization. The union is affiliated with the ASFCME and the AFL-CIO.
  Architects |z New York (State) |z New York.; Collective bargaining |x Engineers.; White collar workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Civil engineers |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Coalition of Black Trade Unionists Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (U.S.)
  The Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU), founded in 1972, consists of members from seventy-seven international and national unions with fifty chapters across the country. It is the independent voice of black workers within the trade union movement, challenging organized labor to be more relevant to the needs and aspirations of black and poor workers.
  African American labor union leaders.; African American labor union members.
- Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions Archived Website, Jul 9, 2011 - Jul 8, 2013; Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions
  The Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions was formed in 1992 to support the organization of new graduate employee unions; to strengthen established unions; and to provide a forum for graduate employee unionists to meet, share information and work together toward common goals. The coalition holds an annual conference featuring workshops on organizing, leadership development, negotiation strategies, and member mobilization. Each year, the conference is hosted by a different union; here are the locations and hosting unions (and international union affiliations) of the past ten conferences. This website is set up in a "wiki" format.
  Graduate teaching assistants -- Labor unions -- United States.
- Coalition of Labor Union Women Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.)
  Formed in 1974, Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) is a nonpartisan organization whose primary mission is to unify all union women in a viable organization to determine our common problems and concerns and to develop action programs within the framework of our unions to deal effectively with our objectives. With members from 54 international and national unions across the U.S. and Canada, CLUW has a network of more than 40 chapters. CLUW is endorsed by the AFL-CIO and its international and national unions.
  Employee rights |z United States.; Women labor union leaders |z United States.; Women labor union members -- United States.
- Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Archived Website, Apr 14, 2014-ongoing; American Federation of School Administrators. Local 1, Council of Supervisors and Administrators (New York, N.Y.)
  The Council of School Supervisors and Administrators is the collective bargaining unit for 6,100 Principals, Assistant Principals, Supervisors and Education Administrators who work in the NYC public schools and 200 Directors and Assistant Directors who work in city- subsidized Centers for Early Childhood Education. CSA was formed from many professional organizations that represented supervisors and administrators as the Council of Supervisory Associations in 1962 to fight for collective bargaining rights with the then NYC Board of Education. In 1968, CSA became a labor union and changed its name to the Council of Supervisors and Administrators. CSA is Local 1 of the American Federation of School Administrators, AFL-CIO, located in Washington, DC. CSA is also affiliated with the NYS Federation of School Administrators, which is, in turn, a member of the NYS School Administrators Consortium. The website contains its newsletter, CSA News, information on workshops and training, political action campaigns, agreements and contracts, and additional photographs and videos.
  Collective bargaining -- School administrators -- United States.
- Communications Workers of America Archived Website, May 24, 2008 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America
  Communications Workers of America (CWA), founded in 1947, is America's largest communications and media union, represents over 700,000 men and women in both private and public sectors, including over half a million workers who are employed in telecommunications, broadcasting, cable TV, journalism, publishing, electronics and general manufacturing, as well as airline customer service, government service, health care, education and other fields. The union includes some 1,200 chartered local unions across the United States, Canada and Puerto Rico. Members live in approximately 10,000 communities, making CWA one of the most geographically diverse unions. CWA is headquartered in Washington, DC, and affiliated with the AFL-CIO, the Canadian Labour Congress, and Union Network International
  Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Communications Workers of America Local 1060 Archived Website, Nov 27, 2012 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1060 (North Plainfield, N.J.)
  CWA Local 1060 represents workers at Lucent (formerly Bell Labs, in Murray Hill, NJ). The website contains information on benefits, minutes, financials, and news.
- Communications Workers of America Local 1109 Archived Website, Nov 26, 2012 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1109
  The Communications Workers of America Local 1109 represents over 2,000 telecommunications technicians and customer service representatives in Brooklyn, New York. The website contains information on benefits, political action campaigns, their publication, the Wire, and news.
- Communications Workers of America, District 1 Archived Website, Mar 7, 2012 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. District 1
  District 1 of the Communications Workers of America (CWA) includes 327 CWA local unions in New York, New Jersey, New England, and eastern Canada. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government.
  Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Middle Atlantic States.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Canada.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New England.
- Communications Workers of America, District 2-13 Archived Website, Mar 2, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. District 2
  District 2-13 is responsible for servicing all CWA locals in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Delaware, Virginia, West Virginia, and the District of Columbia. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government.
  Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z District of Columbia.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z West Virginia.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Maryland.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Virginia.
- Communications Workers of America, District 4 Archived Website, Apr 19, 2014-ongoing; Communications Workers of America. District 4
  Communications Workers of America District 4, representing a variety of workers in the states of Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan and Wisconsin. CWA District 4 includes over 200 local unions that represent workers in telecommunications, informational technology, publishing, print and electronic media, manufacturing, higher education, local government and health care. The website contains news listings, bargaining agreements, their political action committee, and event listings.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1032 Archived Website, Feb 26, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1032 (Ewing, N.J.)
  Communications Workers of America Local 1032 represents about 6,000 workers in a variety of professions and fields in several New Jersey State Departments, the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, several New Jersey towns and counties as well as several private sector work sites.
  Telecommunication |x Labor unions |z New Jersey.; Telecommunication |x Labor unions |z New York.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1101 Archived Website, Feb 27, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1101 (New York, N.Y.)
  Communication Workers of America, Local 1101 is based in New York, New York.
  Telecommunication -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1103 Archived Website, Mar 5, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1103
  Communication Workers of America, Local 1103 is based in Port Chester, New York.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1150 Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1150 (New York, N.Y.)
  Communication Workers of America, Local 1150 is based in New York, NY, and represents landline technicians in the New York and New Jersey metropolitan area. The website contains union news.
  Telephone companies -- Employees -- Labor unions.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 Archived Website, Feb 26, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1153 (Valhalla, N.Y.)
  Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 was chartered in 1975, after more than 500 members of the Manhattan-based Local 1150 petitioned for a new local to represent American Telephone & Telegraph's Long Lines (long distance) employees working in the White Plains and Mount Kisco area. 1153 consists of three sections: Plant (construction and maintenance), Traffic (operators) and Administrative (clerical). Local 1153 advocates for many issues, including job losses, job pressures, seniority rights, the creation of new job titles, health and safety, and discrimination based on sex and race. The website contains by-laws, bargaining reports, other reports, event listings, and contracts.
  Telecommunication -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; American Telephone and Telegraph Company -- Employees
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1180 Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1180 (New York, N.Y.)
  Local 1180 is an affiliate of the Communications Workers of America (CWA), representing over 8,000 workers in the New York City area. Members work in the public sector, but the union also represents workers at the Board of Education, the Housing Authority, the Transit Authority, the School Construction Authority, the state's Unified Court System; at private companies such as the Jacob Javits Convention Center; and at not-for-profit organizations including Planned Parenthood of New York City, the ASPCA, Human Rights First, and Human Rights Watch. The website includes information on health and retiree benefits, training programs, news, negotiations, their newsletter Communique, and other multimedia.
- Domestic Workers United Archived Website, May 4, 2011 - ongoing; Domestic Workers United
  Initially founded in 2000 by the Women Workers Project of Committee of Against Anti-Asian Violence, the Domestic Workers United (DWU) is an organization of Caribbean, Latina and African nannies, housekeepers, and caregivers for the elderly in New York, organizing for fair labor standards and to help build a movement to end exploitation and oppression. DWU organizes workers from the Caribbean, Africa and Latin America, and coordinates with the other domestic workers organizations through the NY Domestic Workers Justice Coalition to build the power of the entire workforce.
  Foreign workers -- United States; Household employees -- United States
- Farm Labor Organizing Committee (FLOC) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Farm Labor Organizing Committee
  The Farm Labor Organizing Committee, AFL-CIO, (FLOC), founded in 1967, is a labor union representing migrant farm workers in the Midwestern United States and North Carolina.
  Hispanic American agricultural laborers.; Agricultural laborers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC), UAW Local 2110 Archived Website, Jul 6, 2011 - Jan 6, 2014; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2110 (New York, N.Y.)
  GSOC/UAW Local 2110 is the union of teaching, research and graduate assistants at New York University. As the chosen representative of the majority of NYU graduate employees, the Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC) is committed to restoring collective bargaining rights for our membership and forcing NYU to once again recognize our union, as it did when GSOC and NYU signed a contract governing graduate employment in 2002. Collective bargaining gives employees a say in their working conditions by empowering chosen representatives of those workers to negotiate with employers over issues like pay, workload protections, workplace safety and benefits.
  Graduate teaching assistants |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York University -- Faculty